MUZABEL WELONGO

in/muzabelwelongo • welongo.dev • https://github.com/mwelongo

SUMMARY

Software Engineer and agile project manager with experience building full-CRUD applications using the MERN Stack (MongoDB, ExpressJS, ReactJS, NodeJS), Python, and PostgreSQL. Entrepreneurial leader with more than five years' experience developing and leading social impact programs, resulting in the creation of more than 2,000 jobs for youth. Sought after for strong analytical and strategic thinking, attention to detail, creativity, business acumen and organizational intuitiveness

SKILLS

- **Software:** HTML, CSS, SASS, Bootstrap, JavaScript ES6, jQuery, RESTful APIs, ReactJS, AngularJS, PHP, NodeJS, Mongoose, MongoDB, MySQL, PostgreSQL, Django, Git/GitHub, WordPress, Heroku
- Digital: Microsoft Office (Word, Excel, PowerPoint,), GSuite, Zendesk, Stata, Power BI, Trello, QuickBooks
- Additional Skills: Agile/Scrum Methodologies, User-Centered Design, Problem Solving, Critical Thinking

SOFTWARE ENGINEERING PROJECTS

Project: Glossa Learning App

Dec 2021

- Concept: A full-CRUD edTech web app to enable individuals to create and deliver online courses
- Built a full-stack app using Django backend, ReactJS, Tailwind CSS framework
- Developed an MVP, wireframed and planned UI design using Canva, before moving to final production.

Project: Travelr Nov 2021

- Concept: An Instagram-like web app for sharing photos, stories and experiences, with location tags.
- A full-stack app built with Django backend and ReactJS, with full CRUD functionalities
- Used Google Maps API and Geolocation API to help users tag and find locations on their posts
- Worked on a team of 3, and was mainly responsible for the MVP/wireframing, GitHub setup, frontend development, CSS styling, and Trello project management

Project: Monnaie Money App

Oct 2021

- Concept: A finTech web app that has functionalities to add/deposit, withdraw, and send money.
- Utilized Node.js, Mongoose, Express and EJS to build a full stack application with full CRUD operations, hitting all RESTful API calls and using a mobile-first styling using CSS3 with flexbox layouts.

Project: Travel Stories App

Nov 2021

- Concept: A web app allowing users to create, update, search and delete stories about visited places
- A full-stack app using Node.js, MongoDB, Express and ReactJS (MERN), with full CRUD functionalities
- Worked on a team of 2, and was responsible for the GitHub collaborative environment setup, ReactJS front-end development, CSS styling, and project management of the project using Trello

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

GENERAL ASSEMBLY

Columbus, OH

Software Engineering Fellow

Sep 2021 - Dec 2021

 Completed a three-month full-stack program, providing experience with the latest front- and back-end programming languages, tools, and methodologies including HTML, CSS, SASS, JavaScript, jQuery, PostgreSQL, MongoDB, Ruby, AngularJS, NodeJS, ReactJS, WordPress, Git, GitHub, and Agile/Scrum.

SENDWAVE Columbus, OH

Growth Manager, US
User Protection Specialist
Risk Support Specialist

Jan 2020 – Feb 2021

Sep 2019 - Jan 2020

Jan 2017 - Aug 2017

- Increased new user acquisition by creating and managing meaningful partnerships with influencers, radio,
 TV, and other media channels, including testing user acquisition strategies
- Leveraged strong cross-cultural communication and sales marketing skills to conduct regular presentations
 of the Sendwave product at churches and diaspora community events
- Analytically reviewed new accounts to detect and prevent potential fraud and provided customer support

RESILIENCE ACTION INTERNATIONAL

Kakuma, Kenya

Founder

Sep 2014 - Dec 2019

- Founded, provided strategic leadership, and led business operations of a non-profit organization that has empowered 15,000+ refugee youth through vocational education, and livelihood development programs
- Grew the team from 3 to 45 in 4 years, and raised more than 1.5 million dollars in grants from foundations

MUZABEL WELONGO

in/muzabelwelongo • welongo.dev • https://github.com/mwelongo

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

Software Engineering Immersive CertificateGENERAL ASSEMBLY

Dec 2021 New York, NY

Master of Global Human Development
GEORGETOWN UNIVERSITY, School of Foreign Service

May 2019 Washington, DC

Bachelor of Social Sciences - Economics
CATHOLIC UNIVERSITY OF EASTERN AFRICA

May 2017 Nairobi, Kenya